Lotteries; Collection mss146
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Lotteries Collection
1790-1883
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
mss146
.39 cubic ft.
This artifical collection contains materials about eighteenth and nineteenth state and private lotteries held in the eastern and midwestern United States.
Content Description
This artifical collection consists of advertisements and broadsides for lotteries, newspaper clippings about lotteries, and lottery tickets.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The exact provenance of this collection is unknown, but these items were all purchased individually by the University Libraries.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Historical Note
This collection documents how the United States in its early decades had both public and private lotteries and how advertisements and broadsides strongly tried to encourage individuals to buy tickets and participate/gamble in these upcoming lotteries.
Advertising--lotteries; Lotteries--United States.; Business and Industry
- Allen Chapin & Co. (Delaware), 1857 (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
- American Monthly Ledger, 1857 (Oversized 1, Folder 2)
- Astor & Co. (Ohio), 1857 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- B.B. Mars & Co., 1853 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Delaware, Missouri and Kentucky State Lotteries, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Delaware & North Carolina Consolidated Lottery, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Delaware State Lotteries, 1857; 1860-1861 (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
- Delaware State Lotteries, 1860; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Delaware State Lotteries, Correspondence, 1860-1861 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- J.H. Bangs & Co. (Maryland), 1855 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Louisiana State Lottery, 1883 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
- Maryland State Lotteries, 1825; 1852; 1855 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Maryland State Lotteries, 1856 (Oversized 1, Folder 5)
- Massachusetts State Lottery, 1790 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- The Monthly Golden Era, 1857 (Oversized 1, Folder 6)
- Mutual Fund Lottery (Ohio), 1857 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Virginia State Lottery, 1837 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Western Consolidated Lotteries, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Western Consolidated Lotteries, 1857 (Oversized 1, Folder 7)